この世界には
善意から生まれる悪意がある
In this world, evil can arise
from the best of intentions.
And there is good which
can come from evil intentions.
悪意から生まれる善意がある
ルルーシュが起こした行動は
In which manner should
Lelouch's actions be taken?
果たして どのように
受け止められるべきものなのか？
裁きは世界の必然なのか？
Is judgment inevitable in this world?
ギアス
Geass.
この人ならざる力を使う者は
Those who use this
superhuman power...
否応なく心に孤独を作り出し
will find their hearts isolated,
whether they want it or not,
善意と悪意の狭間に落ちこんでいく
falling into the gap
between good and evil.
されど もし
But if there is someone who
can manage to climb out of it,
そこから立ち上がる者が
いるとするならば
そう
then that person has the potential to be a king.
その者は 確かなる
王の器を手にしているのだろう
夢見てた夢
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
果て無き遠く
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
等身大 音をたてて
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
キレイに　片方だけ
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
この手に落ちた
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
頭身台 爪をたてて
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
僕の顔　削って行く
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
NUNNALLY HELD HOSTAGE
GUR
GUREN MK-II STARTUP
はい
Yes, re-acclimation training for the post-refit
Guren Mk-II is proceeding as planned.
紅蓮弐式 再調整後の
慣熟訓練は予定通りです
キョウトとインド軍区の間で
話がついた為
There has been talk between Kyoto
and the India military district,
あとは開発チームと
ラクシャータの到着待ちで
so all that's left is to wait for the arrival
of Rakshata from the development team.
ええ　組織の細胞化 現在92％
Yes, the organization's changeover to a
cell-based system is now 92% complete.
構成員も階層１から14まで
割り振ってあります
The members have also been
distributed from class 1 to class 14.
ゼロの指示通り
As Zero has directed, we now have agents
even inside of Britannian-owned warehouses.
ブリタニアが所有している倉庫にも
こちらの協力員を送り込みました
カントウブロック 全564箇所にも
戦力 人員を分散してあります
In all, we have dispersed combat forces and
personnel in 564 places in the Kanto block.
発見された こちらの拠点は32箇所
うちダミーは11箇所
32 of our positions have been spotted,
with 11 of those being dummy ones we set up.
逮捕されたのは 47名ですが
47 of us have been arrested,
階層８以上とは情報が遮断されている為
but since we've compartmentalized
information above class 8 members,
ブリタニアも それ以上は探れません
the Britannians can't learn anything beyond that.
キョウトの後押しもあってか
一般民衆が軍や警察に通報するケースは
With Kyoto backing us, cases
of the general population...
tipping off the military and the
police are becoming more rare.
ほぼ なくなりましたし
ブリタニア内の協力者リストも
And the list of Britannian supporters...
はい　例の
ゼロが手配しておられたグループです
Right, it's the group which you arranged, Zero.
ああ それと
藤堂と四聖剣についてはまだ捜索中です
Also, we're still looking for information
about Tohdoh and the Four Holy Swords.
分かった 引き続き作業を進めろ
Understood. Continue with the work.
いいのか？　私が使者で
Are you sure you want me to be the messenger?
へりくだれば なめられる
そういう相手だろ？　中華連邦は
If you act modestly,
they'll look down on you.
That's how it is with
the Chinese Federation.
自信がないな
私はお前と違って謙虚だから
I'm not confident. Unlike you,
I have a sense of humility.
その調子でやってくれ
Just act exactly like that.
Got your passport?
パスポートは？
よくできている　いけそうだ
It's a good forgery.
I'm ready to go.
私達 また別の家に
預けられるのですか？
Are we going to stay in another house?
また枢木の家だよ
今度は本家の方に行くんだ
It's another of the Kururugi's houses.
We're headed for the main family house this time.
ん…
歩くんだ　スザク
Keep walking, Suzaku.
でも…
But...
歩くんだ
Keep walking.
なんですか？　この変な臭い
What's that strange smell?
ゴミ捨て場の近くなんだ
We're near a garbage dump. Right, Suzaku?
な？　スザク
う… うう…
ん…
う…
スザクさん？　どうしたんですか？
Suzaku, what's wrong?
俺は… 俺が…
I... I!
う…
あ…
ナナリー
Nunnally...
人の体温は涙に効くって
お母様が教えてくれました
My mother taught me that a
warm touch is good for tears.
俺は… 踏み越えてみせる
I have to try and overcome this.
おーい！　ルルーシュ！
Hey! Lelouch!
ん？
おはよう　久しぶりだね
Morning! Haven't seen you in a while.
ちゃんと来ないと留年するよ
You better improve your attendance,
or else you'll get held back.
そっちこそ似たようなものだろ？
The same could be said for you, right?
こっちは仕事
I've got a job. The Black Knights
have been very active lately.
黒の騎士団の動きが
活発になっているから
お前 技術部なんだろ？
I thought you were in the engineering corps.
あぁ…
Um... We're shorthanded all over the place.
手が足りないんだよ　どこも
ふ～ん
でも たまにはうちで
食事でも どうだい？
Still, how about dropping by
for dinner once in a while?
ナナリーが寂しがってる
Nunnally misses you.
Are you free today?
今日の予定は？
あぁ 今晩なら
Yeah, tonight I should be. But should I?
I don't want to cause you any troub... Whoa!
でも いいのかい？　迷惑かけちゃ…
うぅっ！
うおい！　ルルーシュ！
Hey! Lelouch!
どうした？
What's up?
会長 見合いするって知ってたか？
Did you know the president
was meeting a suitor?!
あぁ　今日だろ？
Yeah. Today, right.
今日？
Today?! If you knew,
why didn't you tell me?!
知ってて なんで教えなかった！
教えたら泣くだろ？
Because it would have made you cry.
笑ってみせる
I'll try to smile!
大丈夫　僕も知らなかったから
Don't worry. I didn't know, either.
こんな時に天然で返すな！
This is no time to be so clueless!
天然？
Clueless?
そういうところが天然だっていうんだよ
You have a tendency to be kinda clueless.
じゃあ食事の件 ナナリーに言っても？
Anyway, about dinner.
Shall I tell Nunnally?
うん
Sure. Hey! What about school?!
あぁ！　授業！
分かってる！　教えてくるだけだって！
I know! I'm just going to tell her!
俺の悩みは置き去りですか…
He leaves me behind in my sorrow?!
うふ
あっ
咲世子さん？
Sayoko? My classes don't
start till second period today.
今日の授業は２限目からじゃあ… ん？
ふっ
驚いた？
Are you surprised?
お見合いっていったら
普通はホテルかレストランだものね
These marriage meetings usually
take place in hotels or restaurants.
いえ　ロイド伯爵は
Oh, no. I'd heard you were very
unique person, Lord Lloyd.
大変ユニークな方だと
聞いていましたから
ユニーク！
なかなか すてきな表現だね
Unique! What a wonderful way to put it!
ええ
Yes, and I'm surprised you'd be interested...
爵位をはく奪されて
in a girl from the disgraced
Ashford family after it lost its title.
落ち目のアッシュフォード家の女を
もらおうだなんて
あは　どうでもいいじゃない
爵位なんてさ
Oh ho, but I couldn't care
less about a loss of title.
Excuse me.
失礼します
お手数をおかけします
I'm sorry to be a bother.
どうぞ ごゆっくり
Please, just take your time...
しなくていいよ 時間の無駄だ
No, thank you. No need to waste time.
So, shall we get married?
結婚しよう
え？
早！
That was quick!
んじゃ保留？
Shall we put it on hold, then?
ナナリー　スザクが…
Nunnally! Suzaku is...
あ…
う… うう…
あ！
はい
Yes?
お兄様
Big brother!
ナナリー　今 どこにいるんだ？
Nunnally! Where are you?!
分からないんです
ただ ここから動くなって
I don't know, but I can't move.
あっ
ナナリー！
Nunnally!
僕だよ　ルル
It's me, Lulu!
な！　まさか！
It can't be!
油断したねぇ ルルーシュ
僕が死んだと思ってた？
You let down your guard, Lelouch.
You thought I was dead?
待て マオ！　今C.C.はここにいない
Mao, wait!
C.C. isn't here now!
だから来たんだよ
ギアスの効かない相手は厄介だからね
That's why I came. A opponent immune
to my Geass would just be troublesome.
そっちの件は後回し
I've put off dealing with her.
君に この間のお礼をしないと
僕はもう おさまらないんだ
I won't be satisfied until I've paid
you back for what you did to me.
当然500メートル以内にいるんだろうな
Naturally, you're somewhere
within 500 meters of me.
そういう事
Naturally. Want to try and find me?
探してみるかい？
えいっ！
タイムリミットは５時間
You have 5 hours.
ああ それと
Oh, and since this game is between you
and me, no using the cops as your pawns.
これは僕と君のゲームなんだから
警察の駒を使うのはＮＧだよ
この前みたいに撃たれるのは嫌だから
I prefer not to be shot like before.
でもさ すごいよね
ブリタニアの医学って おかげで
Still, Britannian medical science
really is amazing. I owe it a debt!
ヘヘヘヘヘ…
ねぇ ルル
You know, Lulu, you should
have used your Geass...
あの時のギアスは撃てじゃなくて
殺せと するべきだったんだよ
to have them kill me,
not just shoot me!
詰めが甘いから 妹が…
You left things unfinished,
and now your sister suffers.
窮地に立ったね 危地に陥ったね
ピンチだねぇ
What a predicament!
What a peril! What a pinch!
待て！　ナナリーは関係ない！
Wait! Nunnally has
nothing to do with this!
ゲームにしては悪質じゃありませんか？
Isn't this a bit malicious to just be a game?
んん？
Oh?
お兄様を悲しませるつもりなら
If you're trying to upset my brother,
I'll never forgive you!
あたしが許しません！
ひゃはっ　大したものだね
君達 兄弟は
Oh, brother and sister!
What a pair you make!
皆さーん！　お昼ですよー！
喧嘩？　シャーリーとルルーシュが？
A fight? Shirley and Lelouch?
そっ だから
Yeah, so we're supposed
to play along for a while...
しばらく他人ごっこに
付き合ってやれって 会長がああ…
with them pretending they don't know
each other, the president said... Oh!
どうなったんだろ？　お見合い！
What's going on with that suitor?!
いや そんな事より
シャーリーとルルーシュの…
Never mind that. Shirley and Lelouch...
放っておいたら？
夫婦喧嘩でしょ？　いつもの
Keep out of it. I'm sure it's
just the usual lovers spat.
あれ？　君は…
Huh? Do you know?
あ やだ 関係ないからね　私は
Oh, no way.
It's got nothing to do with me.
どうせ一線を
越えようとしたんじゃないの？
You don't suppose he tried
to cross the line, do you?
一線？
The line?
ほら ルルーシュって知識だけで
実践は弱そうじゃん
Well, Lelouch may be knowledgeable,
but he's not great at putting it into practice.
実践…
Practice...
経験が足りないんだって
I mean he doesn't have enough experience.
経験？
Experience?
ふぅ！
うぅ…
あ ご飯足りなかった？
Oh, didn't he have enough food?
アーサー　どうして君は…
Arthur, why do you always do this?!
はぁ…
よぉ ルルーシュ
シャーリーに何やったんだよ？
Hey, Lelouch! So, what
happened with you and Shirley?
え？　いや…
What? Um...
プレゼントでも贈れば？
Maybe you should give her a present.
それより授業 午後は出ないと…
And what about classes?
You'd better go to the afternoon ones...
あ…
悪い
Excuse me.
Oh, and talk to me later about tonight.
あぁ 夜の件 あとで話そう
ま～だギャンブルを
やってるのかしらねぇ？
You think he's off to gamble again?
ん？
ルル？　逆立ちして探し回ったら
Lulu, if you search for me
while doing a handstand,
タイムリミットを
１時間延長してあげるよ
I'll extend your time limit an hour!
チッ
こちらの焦りは お見通しか
So, he's anticipated my impatience.
But what do I do?
しかし どうする？
俺の心を読む為にも
500メートル以内にいるはずなのだが
He has to be within 500 meters
in order to read my mind, but...
ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
あ！
あ ああ…
あっ それは…
Wha? That's!
うっ…
やっぱり
ナナリーに何かあったんだね？
I thought so. Something's
happened to Nunnally, hasn't it?
お帰りなさい
Welcome back.
えっ？
What? Uh... Hi.
あっ た ただいま
すぐ お食事できますから
The food's almost ready.
食事って…
Food? What, you went shopping?
Outside?
買い物に出たんですか？　外に
いえ　あり合わせですから
No, I just made
what I could find here.
外は まだブリタニアが怖くって
Outside, they're still
afraid of Britannia, so...
何か思い出した事は？
Have you been able
to remember anything?
すみません　何も…
Sorry. Nothing yet.
いいんですよ　慌てなくても
That's okay.
Nothing to worry about.
怪我の事もあるし…
You're still injured.
Just take your time and try to remember.
ゆっくり 思い出してくれればいい
さぁ できました
お口に合うといいんですけど
Okay, all done.
I hope it's to your taste.
あ え？
Uh...
誰なんだ？　ナナリーをさらったのは
まさか ブリタニアの皇室？
So, who's kidnapped Nunnally?
It's not the Britannian royal family, is it?
いや　俺達の出自には関係ない
No, this has nothing
to do with our blood ties.
女を独り占めしたいってだけの
ただのガキだよ
It's some kid who
wants a girl all to himself.
脅されているのか？
So, he's threatening you?
そうだ
An official investigation
may reveal who we are.
取調べを受けると
俺達の事がバレるかもしれない
だから軍や警察には…
That's why I can't go
to the army or the police.
仕方ないな
僕達だけで なんとかするしかない
It can't be helped. We'll just have
to do something on our own.
でも 本当にギャンブルとか…
But, is this about your gambling?
関係ないって
I said it isn't!
じゃあ手がかりになる物は？
Okay, what are our clues?
写真と俺を見張れるぐらい
近くにいるって事しか…
Just this photo and that
he's nearby, watching me.
あっ そういえば
水が流れているような音が！
And now that I think of it, I heard
the sound of running water!
水？
Water...
循環システム
The water circulation system!
下の階層か
The lower levels?
でも珍しいな
Still, this is rare.
何が？
What?
いつもの君なら すぐ気づくのに
Normally, you would have
realized this right away.
えぃ…
Damn!
どうしたの？
What?
データが変えられている
ロックシステムを破るしかない
He's changed the data.
We'll just have to break the lock system.
それって校則違反じゃ？
That's against school rules!
あとで直しておく
I'll fix it later.
だったら僕が壊すから
Then let me break it...
残念　もう開いた
Too bad. It's open.
早いな　手馴れ過ぎてないか？
That was fast.
You're a little too good at that.
管理の一部は
生徒会が受け持っているからな
The student council has partial
access to the maintenance systems.
ルルーシュ
Lelouch, you've been using this
to get off campus, haven't you?
今までも これを使って
外に抜け出したりしていただろ？
ん？　あぁ たまにね
Hm? Yeah, occasionally.
どうだ？
Well?
君の推察通りだ
Just like you guessed.
監視カメラに
マシンガンを連動させている
He's linked a machine gun
to the security camera.
あのシステムなら
タイムラグはおよそ 0.05
That system only has
a time lag of 0.05 seconds.
じゃあ ここからは出られないな
一度 上に戻ってシステム…
So, we can't get out of here.
We'll head back up and disable the system...
えぃっ
あっ おい！
Hey!
乱暴な奴だな
Of all the reckless!
さぁ 行こう　ナナリーが待っている
All right, let's go!
Nunnally's waiting for us!
ナナリー！
Nunnally!
あっ お兄様　スザクさんも？
Big brother? Suzaku?
ごめん　今すぐ
I'm sorry! I'll get you down right...
待って
Wait! Up there!
上を
あ…
爆弾
A bomb.
そうだよ ルル
That's right, Lulu!
勝手についてきた枢木までは許すから
２人で頑張ってみてね
I allowed Kururugi to join in on this.
Now show me how you two deal with this.
くぅ…
ナナリー 僕達が爆弾を外す
大丈夫　安心して
Nunnally, we're going
to get rid of the bomb.
It's okay. Just stay calm.
僕とルルーシュが組んで
できなかった事なんて ないだろ？
There's nothing Lelouch
and I can't do together, right?
あ… はい
Right!
ふっふふふ…
振り子爆弾か
That's a pendulum bomb.
いつまでも運動が止まらないように
A solenoid inside supplies it
with energy to keep it swinging.
ソレノイドが
エネルギーを与え続けている
もし それ以外の力が加わった場合
爆弾は…
If an external force acts on it, the bomb will...
爆発する
Explode. And we should assume
it'll blow if we move Nunnally, too.
そして 恐らくナナリーを動かしても…
そう考えた方がいいね
被害規模は分かるか？
Can you guess its destructive range?
半径500メートル以上は…
Up to a 500 meter radius, I think.
という事は
マオはギアスの有効範囲外にいる
Does that mean Mao is out
of range to use his Geass?
誘いか これも…
Is this another lure for me?
解体の方法は分かる？
You know how to disarm it?
理屈はな
In theory.
起爆装置から出ているラインを
切断するだけ
We just have to cut the power
line coming from the detonator.
あいつは本職じゃないから
ダミーを割り出す事は可能だ
Since he's not a pro, we could figure
out which line is the dummy one.
しかし… 他の方法を考えないと
Still, we have to think
of another way to do it.
どうして？　区別さえつけば
Why? If we can just figure
out which one to cut...
ごくわずかな揺れ幅の中で
あれを切断する
Cutting the right one without disturbing the others?
That's beyond human ability.
人間業じゃない
分かった　僕がやろう
All right, then I'll do it.
簡単に言うな！　情報が少なすぎる
It's not that easy!
We don't know enough about this!
慎重なのもいいけど
タイムリミットがあるんだろ？
It's fine to play it safe,
but we're fighting a time limit, right?
それに情報なら君の目の前にある
Besides, all you need to know
is right here in front of you.
僕は これでも軍人だ
この情報を使えないか？
I'm also a soldier.
Can't you use what I know, too?
ふん…
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
ふ～ふふぅん ふっふふっふふ～ん
ふ～ふふぅん
トイレットペーパーは まだあるし
I just need to get some toilet paper...
ん？
う～ん 授業かったりぃ
Man, this class sucks so bad...
とりあえず卒業まで遊ばなくっちゃ
For now, I've gotta goof off till graduation.
School regulations my ass!
学校早退してぇ
バカ教師のくせに…
Who does that idiot teacher think he is?
お気楽なガキどもめ
これだから学校ってやつは！
Easygoing kids!
No wonder I hate schools!
へぇ
Oh?
なんだ？
What now?
What's Mao set up for me next?
次は何を仕掛けてくるつもりだ？
マオの居場所は
ナナリーを監視しているカメラの送信先
Mao is wherever that camera
watching Nunnally is transmitting to.
まさか学校に戻っているとはな
I never thought
he'd go back to the school.
ふざけた奴だ
That damned clown!
スザクには動くなと伝えてあるが
もはや 俺に残された手は…
I told Suzaku not to make any moves,
but that just leaves me one option.
ようこそ！　泥棒猫君
Welcome, my dear little thief!
武器も作戦もなく 爆弾もそのまま
No weapons, no plans,
and you left the bomb alone.
黒の騎士団も さっきのお友達も
使っていないねぇ
And you didn't use the Black
Knights or your friend from before.
どうしちゃったの？　ルル
What's wrong, Lulu?
分かりきった会話をする気はない
I have no intention of
discussing the obvious with you.
用意してあるんだろ？　ラストゲームを
Do you have things
ready for our last game?
う～ん　決着をつけよう
Yes, let's put an end to this.
君の得意技で
Using your specialty.
ん？
久しぶりだな　こういう時間は
It's been such a long time since
we could spend time like this.
There've been too many unexpected things
that have happened since we came to Area 11.
エリア11に来て以来
予想外の事が多すぎた
きゃぁ！
デスクワークばかりで
太ったんじゃないか？
All that desk work's making you fat, isn't it?
もうっ お姉様ったらぁ
Oh, sis, lay off!
あはははは　ふふっ
お姉様 このお庭 似ていると
思いませんか？　マリアンヌ様の離宮に
Sis, don't you think this garden looks familiar?
Like the one at Lady Marianne's villa?
ああ そういえば
Yes, now that you mention it.
クロヴィス兄様が指示したんですって
They say Clovis directed
that it be built like this.
意外と気に入っていたのだな
I'm surprised
he liked it so much.
あそこのルルーシュとは
喧嘩ばかりしていたくせに
Even though he'd always be
fighting with Lelouch there.
ライバルだったんですよ　きっと
He must have seen
Lelouch as his rival.
相手は年下だぞ？
Even though Lelouch was younger than him?
でも 兄様が遺した絵の中に
Still, Lelouch and the others show
up in the paintings he left behind.
ルルーシュ達を
描いた物がありましたよ
そうか
Really?
早く このエリアを平定し
ゼロを捕まえねばな
We need to stabilize this area
and arrest Zero soon.
クロヴィスに…
For Clovis...
そしてルルーシュやナナリーにも
申し訳が立たん
And as an apology
for Lelouch and Nunnally.
ここは兄弟３人が
命を散らせた天地なのだから
This land has cost us the
lives of three of our siblings.
この天秤はねぇ
This scale is connected to the bomb's
detonator and to a cancellation switch.
爆弾の起爆装置でもあり
解除スイッチでもあるんだ
乗せるのは互いに取り合った駒
We will place on it the chess
pieces we each capture.
この目盛りが
完全に僕の方へ傾けば爆発
If the needle tips all the way
towards me, the bomb explodes.
君の方に傾けば爆弾は解除される
If it tips toward you,
the bomb is disarmed.
つまり 君が勝てば妹は
助かるって事さ
In short, if you win,
your sister's life is saved.
趣味が悪いな　C.C.に捨てられる訳だ
Your taste is repellent.
No wonder C.C. left you.
挑発は通じないよ
君の心は丸分かりなんだから
Provoking me won't work.
I can read your mind completely.
君は頭を空っぽにできるタイプじゃない
You aren't the type who
can keep his mind clear.
いつだって自分の行動を見ている
批評家の自分がいて
There's the part of you that's the critic,
constantly watching your own moves...
その批評家の自分を
and the part of you who
coolly observes the critic.
冷めて見つめている
もう１人の自分がいて
That's the sort of person you are.
そういう人間だよ
ふふ　無駄だよ
どれだけ考えようと僕の勝利は動かない
It's hopeless. No matter how you
think, my victory remains assured.
くぅ くっ！
すごい！　７つの事を同時に考えて
僕を惑わせようって作戦だね
Bravo!
Your plan is to think of seven things
at once in order to confuse me?
でもねぇ
僕のギアスを君だけに絞れば
The thing is, if I confine
my Geass to just you,
何が真実か読み取るのは簡単さ
it's simple to read your real thoughts.
な！
Oh, dear, I'm afraid your
final plan won't work, either.
あぁ あぁ 最後の策も駄目だった
僕をみくびるから妹の命が
Since you think so little of me,
your sister is going to die.
な…
う… あ…
どうしよう　もう策がない
What will you do now?
You're out of strategies.
他人を使おうにも
ナナリーを人質に捕られている以上
Even though you can use others,
as long as Nunnally is held hostage, then...
あ！
ごめん ごめん　落としちゃったぁ
Sorry, I dropped it.
はぁ…
あっ！
君の番だよ？　急がないと
ほらほら 時間がなくなっちゃうよ
Your turn. Better hurry.
Come on, come on,
time is running out.
妹がいなくなっちゃうよ？
Your little sister's going to die.
へぇ そんな手でいいんだ
Oh, please! Make that move!
本当にいいのぉ？
You sure you want to do that?
あ… あぁ　もう いいだろ
Isn't this enough?
あ？
やめてくれ　マオ
Please stop this, Mao.
よぉく聞こえないなぁ
I can't hear you that well.
もう十分だろ ナナリーを助けてくれ！
You've gotten what you want!
Let Nunnally go!
Oh?
はぁ？
俺の… 俺の負けだ
I've... I've lost to you.
ふっ ふふっ ふははは
ははははははは
ははははははは！
よく言えました
Well said!
ようやく君の心の底からの声を
聞かせて もらえましたねぇ
You've finally spoken to me
from the bottom of your heart!
気持ちいい！　最高！
Oh, it feels wonderful!
Fantastic!
でも駄目
But no use.
はっ
これで
This move...
あ！
チェックだ
is check.
NO!!!
やめろぉー！
はぁ… ナナリー…
Nunnally...
さぁて どんな感じでバラバラに？
So, how's it feel to have
her get blown to pieces?
ん？
ええ？
なぜ？　どうして？
What the? Why isn't she?!
え？
Did you?! You kept me
concentrating on you so that?!
まさか！　僕の意識を集中させて？
どわ！
ぐぅっ！
自分はブリタニア軍准尉 枢木スザクだ
治安じょう乱の容疑で君を拘束する
I am Warrant Officer Suzaku
Kururugi of the Britannian military.
You're under arrest
for disturbing the peace!
スザク…
Suzaku...
爆弾を解体した？　え？
You disarmed the bomb?!
そんな…
振り子とスピードを合わせて？
Impossible... You matched
the speed of the pendulum?!
どのラインを切ればいいかは
ルルーシュが教えてくれたからね
Because Lelouch showed
me which line I should cut.
俺が教えた？
I showed you?
何言ってるんだい？
君の指示だろ？
What are you saying?
These were your instructions, weren't they?
叫び声が聞こえたら 突入しろって事も
Including me busting in here
if I heard you scream.
俺が？
I did?
あっ は！
やはり…
Of course...
そうか
That's it.
マオ　これでチェックメイトだよ
Mao, this makes it checkmate for me.
ルルーシュ　まさかお前は！
Lelouch, don't tell me you!
そうらしいな
Apparently so.
俺はスザクに指示した事を
自分にギアスをかけて忘れさせた
After I gave Suzaku his instructions,
I used my Geass on myself to make me forget.
Your belief that the mind's voice is the
ultimate source of information led to your loss.
心の声は絶対的な情報だと信じた
お前の負けだ
それに俺の心を読む為に
効果範囲を絞ったのが 仇になったな
And confining the range of your power
to read my mind was your downfall.
バカな…
Impossible!
こいつが失敗したら
どうするつもりだったんだ？
What would you have done
if he had failed?!
そうだな
Good point. I couldn't have made
this plan work if I didn't trust Suzaku.
これはスザクを信じていないと
取れない作戦
咲世子さん もうＯＫです
はい　お願いします
Sayoko? Everything's fine now.
Right, if you could.
Sayoko?
咲世子さん
もう大丈夫ですよ
You're safe now.
ふん
You think you've beaten me now?!
それで勝ったつもりか！
よせ
Stop it!
Unhand me, you father killer!
放せよ この父親殺しが！
は！
ん？
お前は７年前に実の父親を殺している
You killed your own
father seven years ago!
ふん
徹底抗戦を唱えていた父親を止めれば
戦争は終わる？
You thought stopping your father, who called
for total resistance, would end the war?
子供の発想だね
What a childish way of thinking!
実際は ただの人殺し
The fact is, you're nothing but a murderer.
違う！　僕は… 俺は…
That's not true! I... I just!
良かったね　バレなくて
It's a good thing no one ever found out,
周りの大人達が
み～んなで嘘をついたおかげさ
thanks to all the adults around
you who lied for your sake.
それじゃあ 枢木首相が自決する事で
軍部をいさめたって…
You mean, the story that Prime Minister Kururugi
committed suicide to protest the military...
...was a gigantic lie. All of it.
大嘘だよ　何もかも
嘘？
A lie...
I had no choice!
If I hadn't, Japan would have been...
仕方がなかった！
そうしなければ日本は…
今さら後づけの理屈かい？
Is that how you rationalize it now?
Is it, Mr. Death Wish?!
この死にたがりが！
ああ！
人を救いたいって？
救われたいのは自分の心だろ？
You want to save people?
It's your own soul
that you want to save.
それに殉じて死にたいんだよねぇ？
You want to sacrifice
your life, don't you?!
だから いつも自分を死に追い込む！
That's why you keep risking yourself!
うっ…
うわぁー！
Your good intentions are just
for your own self-satisfaction!
お前の善意はただの自己満足なんだよ！
You're just a naive boy
who wants to be punished!
罰が欲しいだけの甘えん坊め！
マオ！
MAO!
んっ？
NEVER SPEAK AGAIN!
お前は黙っていろ！
Oh, hell!
しまった！
が… あ…
があ… あ… あ…
う…
あ… う…
ふん！
待て！
Stop!
好きだったよ　マオ
I did love you, Mao.
かはは… あ…
マオ
Mao... Go and wait for me. In C's world.
先に行って待っていろ
Ｃの世界で
あ！
う…
俺は…
I...
I!
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
意味もなく繰り返し
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
過去の嘘も過ちも
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
I'm a fool.
俺は愚か者だ
In the end, I never asked Mao about
the contract he made with C.C.
結局マオに契約の事は聞けないまま
And Suzaku...
そしてスザク
Why, when we were reunited, did he?
No, I'm wrong.
なぜ再会した時に…
いや 違う
He's been making it clear
for a long time now.
昔からあいつは伝えようとしていたんだ
At that time, even if I had
been the one facing him...
あの時 俺が向き合ってさえいたら
KNIGHT